那是1956年。
It's 1956.
一名年轻的程序员正带着他的女朋友在阿姆斯特丹逛街，他并不知道自己即将开发出
A young programmer is taking his girlfriend shopping in Amsterdam without knowing that he would develop one of the most important
历史上最重要的算法之一。
algorithms in history.
没人能预料到，仅仅在20分钟内，我们所熟知的世界就会发生巨变。
No one could possibly know that in just 20 minutes the world as we knew it would be transformed.
那是后来成为享誉世界的荷兰程序员和数学家 Edsger W.
That was the day when a soon-to-be a world-renowned Dutch programmer and mathematician, Etsker W.
Dijkstra，构思出一个将驱动GPS导航、网络路由、社交网络、
Dijkstra, came up with an algorithm that would power GPS navigation, network routing, social media networks,
供应链、机器人技术等领域的算法。
supply chains, robotics, and more.
他就在我们喝一杯咖啡的时间里，彻底改变了世界。
He literally changed the world in the time it takes us to drink a cup of coffee.
你能想象吗？
Can you imagine that?
Edsger Dijkstra 出生于1930年，在荷兰的鹿特丹。
Edgar Dijkstra was born in 1930 in Rotterdam, in the Netherlands.
他在荷兰莱顿的莱顿大学学习数学和物理。
He studied mathematics and physics at Leiden University in Leiden, Netherlands.
让我们来看看他的算法，以及他如何描述那天发生的事情。
Let's take a look at his algorithm and how he described what happened that day.
1956年，Dijkstra 在阿姆斯特丹的数学中心担任程序员。
In 1956, Dijkstra was working as a programmer at the Mathematical Center in Amsterdam.
当时该中心即将推出一台开创性的荷兰计算机，也就是全新的 RMAC 电脑。
The center was about to unveil a pioneering Dutch computer, the new RMAC computer.
他想通过选择一个足够有挑战性、能让人们感到惊喜的问题来展示这台电脑的威力，
He wanted to showcase the power of this computer by choosing a problem that would be challenging enough to surprise people,
但这个问题又要足够通用，让那些不是计算机专业的人也能理解，甚至觉得有趣。
but general enough so that people who were not specialized in computing could still understand it and even find it interesting.
他选择了寻找两个地点之间最短路径的问题。
He chose the problem of finding the shortest path between two locations.
他问：电脑如何找到从A点到B点最有效的方法？
He asked, How can a computer find the most efficient way to get from point A to point B?
他在工作期间和下班后一直在思考这个问题。
He kept thinking about this during and after his work hours.
令人惊讶的是，灵感在最意想不到的时刻出现了。
Surprisingly, inspiration came during the most unexpected moment.
那天，当 Dijkstra 和他的女朋友逛累了时，他们坐在咖啡馆的露台上喝了一杯咖啡。
When Dijkstra and his girlfriend felt tired from walking around the shops that day, they sat down at a cafe terrace to drink a cup of coffee.
他一直在思考，就在不停地思考。
He kept thinking, he just kept thinking.
他如何找到从荷兰的两个城市——鹿特丹到格罗宁根的最短路径？
How could he find the shortest way to travel from Rotterdam to Groningen, the two cities in the Netherlands?
他最初从这个非常具体的问题开始，但随后他意识到让问题更通用具有巨大的潜力。
He started with that very specific question, but then he realized the potential of making the question more general.
与其只考虑两个城市，为什么不给出一个通用的解决方案，来寻找任意两个给定城市之间的最短路径呢？
Instead of only considering two cities, why not come up with a general solution that would find the shortest path between any two given cities?
令人惊讶的是，用他自己的话说，这个解法是经过20分钟的构思才发明的。
Surprisingly, in his own words, the solution was a 20-minute invention.
只要20分钟，仅需20分钟。
20 minutes, that's all it took.
就在他喝完咖啡时，我们现在所熟知的 Dijkstra 算法的基本逻辑已经成型。
By the time he had finished his coffee, the fundamental logic of what we now know as Dijkstras' algorithm was complete.
而且这个算法不仅是正确的，还为我们今天使用的许多现代系统奠定了基础。
And the algorithm was not only correct, but also provided the foundation for many of the modern systems that we use nowadays.
该算法在三年后的1959年正式发表。
The algorithm itself was formally published three years later in 1959.
你现在仍然可以在网上读到最初发表的论文。
You can still read the original publication yourself, online.
它的名字叫《关于与图相关的两个问题的一点说明》。
It's called A Note on Two Problems in Connection with Graphs.
要理解 Dijkstra 的贡献，你需要了解它的基本原理。
To appreciate what Dijkstra came up with, you need to understand its underlying principles.
那我们现在就开始深入探讨。
So let's dive in.
首先，什么是算法？
First of all, what is an algorithm?
算法是解决问题或达到目标时，需要遵循的一系列非常具体、明确的步骤指令。
An algorithm is a sequence of very, very specific and unambiguous step-by-step instructions that you follow to solve a problem or reach a solution.
软件开发人员使用编程语言来实现这些算法，让计算机按照它们能理解的语言一步步执行这些指令。
Software developers use programming languages to implement these algorithms, making computers follow those instructions step by step in a language they understand.
为了找到任意两个城市之间的最短路径，Dijkstra 必须以更抽象的方式去思考城市之间的可能路径，
To find the shortest path between any two given cities, Dijkstra had to think about the possible paths between the cities in a more abstract way,
来表示它们与路径上任何其他城市之间的连接。
representing the connections between them and any other cities in the path.
他通过将现实世界中的道路和城市转化为一种被称为「图」的数据结构来实现这一点。
He did this by translating the physical world of roads and cities into a data structure called graph.
在计算机科学中，你可以把“图”理解为表示事物之间关系或连接的一种方式。
You can think of a graph as a way to represent relationships or connections between things in computer science.
图有两个主要组成部分：节点和边。
Graphs have two main components, nodes and edges.
你可以把节点看作是那些相互连接的事物。
You can think of the nodes as the things that are connected.
在 Dijkstra 算法中，节点代表城市。
In Dijkstra's algorithm, nodes represent cities.
通过将世界视为一系列节点和边的组合，Dijkstra 算法可以应用于几乎任何领域，而不只是道路和城市。
By viewing the world as a series of nodes and edges, Dijkstra's algorithm can be applied to almost anything, not just roads and cities.
在不同的场景下，它们可以代表不同的事物：社交媒体平台上的用户、供应链中的仓库、计算机网络中的路由器，
They could represent different things in different contexts: users in social media platforms, warehouses in supply chains, routers in computer networks,
还有电子游戏中的地图方格，等等。
tiles in video games, and much more.
这里的关键点是，节点代表那些以某种方式相连的事物。
The key takeaway here is that nodes represent things that are somehow connected.
这些连接就是图的边。
These connections are the edges of the graph.
但仅仅知道城市是连接在一起的，还不足以解决 Dijkstra 的问题。
But just knowing that the cities are connected is not enough to solve Dykstra's problem.
你还需要更多信息。
You need more information than that.
记住，他当时是在试图寻找两个城市之间的最短路径。
Remember that he was trying to find the shortest path between two cities.
为了找到它，也就是最短路径，你需要知道与每个连接或每条边相关的成本。
To find it, to find the shortest path, you need to know the cost associated with each connection or edge.
这被称为边的权重。
This is known as the weight of the edge.
在 Dijkstra 的问题中，权重代表两个城市之间的距离，或者在它们之间行驶所需的时间，
In Dykstra's problem, weights would represent the distance between two cities, or the time it takes to travel between them,
也就是一个某种程度上代表这种连接的抽象数值。
an abstract quantity that somehow represents that connection.
然而，边的权重在不同的场景下可能有不同的含义。
However, edge weight can have different meanings in different contexts.
例如，两个用户之间的连接数量，图像中不同区域像素之间的颜色相似度，或者电子游戏中从一个方格移动到另一个方格的成本，
The number of connections between two users, for example, color similarity between pixels in different regions of an image, the cost of moving from one tile to another in a video game,
等等还有更多。
and more.
当图的边具有这些权重时，这个图就被分类为“加权图”。
When the edges of a graph have weights like these, the graph is classified as a weighted graph.
Dijkstra 算法适用于这类图。
Dijkstras algorithm works with this type of graph.
它利用权重来寻找最短路径，也就是总权重最低的那条路径。
It uses the weights to find the shortest path, the path with the lowest total weight.
让我们通过一个实际的例子来看看这个算法是如何运作的。
Let's see the algorithm in action with a practical example.
假设你正从源节点 A 前往目的地节点 D，而这是城市或节点之间的整体连接情况。
Imagine you're traveling from source node A to destination node D, and this is the overall connection of the cities or the nodes.
节点 A 被称为源节点，也就是你开始整个过程的地方。
Node A is known as the source node, where you're starting the process.
算法首先给每个节点分配一个距离值。
The algorithm starts by assigning a distance value to each node.
它将源节点到自身的距离设为 0，而将源节点到图中所有其他节点的距离设为无穷大。
It sets the distance from the source node to itself to zero, and the distance from the source node to all other nodes in the graph to infinity.
这里的「无穷大」只是临时使用的，表示算法目前还不知道这些节点的信息，因为还没访问过它们。
Infinity is only used temporarily here to represent that the algorithm doesn't know anything about those nodes yet because it hasn't visited them.
算法还会记录哪些节点已经被访问过。
Visited nodes are also tracked.
然后，算法开始从源节点 A 开始。
Then the algorithm starts by visiting node A, the source node.
这是起点。
This is the starting point.
它会检查未访问的邻居节点。
It checks its unvisited neighbors.
在这种情况下，这些邻居节点包括距离 A 为 2 的 B 节点（你可以从图表中的距离或权重看到），以及距离 A 为 6 的 C 节点。
In this case, these nodes, the neighbors, are node B with a distance of 2 from node A. You can see the distances or weights over here in the diagram, and node C with a distance of 6 from node A.
由于它们的这些新距离比当前记录的距离要小（记住我们最初设定的都是无穷大），所以它们会被更新。
Since their new distances are smaller than their current distances, remember that we assigned infinity initially, they are updated.
它们的上一个节点也会被更新为 A。
Their previous node is also updated to node A.
只有当路径变短、也就是我们找到更好的、更短的路径时，才会更新距离。
We only update the distances if they are shorter, if we find a better path, a shorter path.
记录节点的序列（就像我们在表格中记录的上一个节点一样）有助于我们在找到最终解后重构出最短路径。
Tracking the sequence of nodes, like the previous nodes that we have here in the table, is helpful to recreate the shortest path once we reach the final solution.
最后，在这一步中，当我们检查完所有邻居并更新了它们的距离后，A 就会被标记为已访问。
And finally, in this step, node A is marked as a visited once we checked all the neighbors and updated their distances.
接着，算法会去访问下一个总边权最小的未访问节点。
Then the algorithm visits the next unvisited node with the lowest total edge weight.
在这个图中，那就是 B 节点，因为它到 A 的距离是 2。
In this graph, that would be node B, since its distance from node A is 2.
所以我们来访问 B 节点。
So let's visit node B.
我们需要检查它的未访问邻居。
We need to check its unvisited neighbors.
这个节点的邻居是 A、C 和 D。
The neighbors of this node are node A, node C, and node D.
但 A 已经被访问过了。
But node A was already visited.
所以这一步我们只考虑 C 和 D。
So we only consider nodes C and D in this step.
让我们从 C 开始。
Let's start with node C.
如果我们选择经过 B 的路径，那么从 A 到 C 的距离将是 2 加 9，
If we choose a path that goes through node B, the distance from node A to node C would be 2 plus 9,
也就是 11。
which is 11.
然而，在我们的表格中，记录的通过之前探索过的另一条路径从 A 到 C 的距离是 6。
However, in our table we have a distance of 6 recorded from node A to node C through a different path that we explored previously.
由于经过 B 的路径比我们目前记录的要长，所以我们不更新距离，而是保留当前的值。
Since taking the path through node B would be longer than what we currently have recorded, we don't update the distance, we just keep the current one.
现在我们到节点 D。
Now let's go to node D.
如果我们选择经过节点 B 的路径，从节点 A 到节点 D 的距离就是 2 加 5，
If we choose a path that goes through node B, the distance from node A to node D would be 2 plus 5,
也就是 7。
which is 7.
这比我们目前记录的距离要短。
This is less than the distance that we currently have recorded.
目前是无穷大，所以 7 肯定更好。
Currently it is infinity, so 7 is definitely better.
我们更新这个距离，并将前一个节点改为 B。
We update this distance and the previous node to node B.
最后，我们将节点 B 标记为已访问。
Finally, we mark node B as visited.
现在我们需要访问下一个未访问且总边权最小的节点。
Now we need to visit the next unvisited node with the smallest total edge weight.
在这个图中，那就是节点 C，因为它的距离目前是 6，而从 A 到 B 的距离是 7。
In this graph that would be node C, because its distance is currently 6, while the distance to node B from node A is 7.
所以我们去访问节点 C。
So let's visit node C.
我们需要检查节点 C 的未访问邻居。
We need to check the unvisited neighbors of node C.
节点 C 有三个邻居：A、B 和 D，因为你可以看到它与这些节点有连接，也就是有边。
Node C has three neighbors, node A, node B, and node D since you can see that it has connections with those nodes, it has edges.
但是，由于 A 和 B 已经被标记为已访问，我们只需要检查节点 D。
However, nodes A and B are already marked as visited, so we only need to check node D.
从节点 C 到节点 D 的距离是 8。
The distance from node C to node D is eight.
通过节点 C 从 A 到 D 的总距离是 6 加 8，也就是 14。
The total distance from node A to node D, going through node C, would be six plus eight, which is 14.
目前我们记录的从 A 到 D 的距离是 7。
Currently, the distance that we've recorded from node A to node D is seven.
所以我们保留当前的这个。记住，我们一直在寻找更好的路径，也就是更短的路径。
So we just keep the current one. Remember that we're always looking for a better path, a shorter path.
如果不是更短的，我们就不会更新它。
If it's not shorter, then we don't update it.
而且由于那是节点 C 唯一的未访问邻居，我们将其标记为已访问。
And since that's the only unvisited neighbor of node C, we mark it as visited.
最后，我们前往下一个权重最低的未访问节点。
Finally, we go to the next unvisited node with the lowest total weight.
在这种情况下，只有一个未访问的节点，就是节点 D。
In this case, there's only one unvisited node, which is node D.
由于节点 D 的所有邻居都已被检查并访问，我们只需将其标记为已访问。
Since all the neighbors of node D have already been checked and visited, we just mark it as visited.
我们将节点 D 标记为已访问。
We mark node D as visited.
算法停止了，因为所有节点都已访问，过程也完成了。
And the algorithm stops since all nodes have been visited and the process has been completed.
现在我们有了最终结果，要找到从 A 到 D 的最短路径，我们需要根据记录的前一节点序列进行回溯。
Now that we have the final result, to find the shortest path from node A to node D, we need to backtrack using the sequence of previous nodes that we've recorded.
从节点 D 开始，我们回到节点 B。
From node D, we go to node B.
然后从节点 B 回到节点 A，正如你在表格中看到的，我们是反向操作的。
And then from node B we go to node A, as you can see here in the table, we're going backwards.
所以如果我们从节点 A 开始，
So if we start from node A,
序列就是：节点 A、节点 B 和节点 D。
the sequence would be node A, node B, and node D.
这就是这个图中从 A 到 D 的最短路径。
And that's the shortest path from node A to node D in this graph.
我们做到了！
We did it!
太棒了！
Awesome!
在视频的这个实操部分，大家做得很好。
Great work in this practical part of the video.
这里有一个重要的收获是，这个算法始终选择权重最小的连接
An important takeaway here is that this algorithm consistently selects the connections with the smallest weights
并记录哪些节点已经访问过，哪些还没有被访问。
and keeps track of which nodes have been visited and which nodes have not been visited so far.
关于 Dijkstra 算法，你还需要知道的另一件重要的事情是，它被归类为贪心算法。
Another important thing that you should know about Dijkstra's algorithm is that it's classified as a greedy algorithm.
你可能会问为什么叫贪心？嗯，因为它非常、非常、非常贪心。
And you may ask why greedy? Well, because it's very, very, very greedy.
它在每一步中都选择当前最好的可能选项。
It chooses the best possible option in each step.
基本上，每当它需要做决定时，都会选择看起来最好的路径。
Basically, it chooses the path that looks best whenever it has to make a decision.
让我们深入一点，看看 Dijkstra 算法的 Python 实现，看看如何在代码中实现这个算法。
Let's dive a little bit deeper and check out a Python implementation of Dykstra's algorithm to see how you can implement this algorithm in code.
在我们深入探讨实际的 Dijkstra 函数细节之前，先来看看如何在代码中表示一个图，因为我们需要用到它。
Before we dive into the details of the actual Dijkstra function, let's see how you can represent a graph in code, because we will need it.
记住，图是这个算法的核心，它是在 Dijkstra 问题背景下代表城市及其连接的核心数据结构。
Remember that graphs are the core of this algorithm, the core data structures that represent the cities and their connections in the context of Dykstra's problem.
这是我们图中所示图形的 Python 表示方式。
This is a Python representation of the graph that we have in the diagram.
这里我们使用 Python 字典来表示我们所熟知的邻接表，它基本上就是一个字典
Here we're using a Python dictionary to represent what we know as an adjacency list, which is basically a dictionary
在 Python 中包含其他字典。
in Python that contains dictionaries.
这些字典代表图中哪些节点与其他节点相邻。
These dictionaries represent which nodes are adjacent to other nodes in the graph.
主字典的键是图中的所有节点，它们关联到表示与其相连节点的字典，
The keys of the main dictionary are all the nodes in the graph, and they are associated to dictionaries that represent the nodes that they are connected to,
以及连接它们的边的权重。
and the weights of the edges that connect them.
例如，如你所见，节点 A 与节点 C 相连，它们通过一条权重为 6 的边相连。
For example, as you can see here, node A is connected to node C, and they are connected through an edge of weight 6.
这就是你如何理解这些邻接表的。
So that's how you can interpret these adjacency lists.
很好，既然你已经知道我们如何表示图了，现在来看看实际的函数实现。让我们看看 Dijkstra 函数的实现。
Great, now that you know how we'll represent the graph, let's check out the actual function implementation. Let's check out Dijkstra's function implementation.
我们首先导入一个 Python 内置模块，用于创建优先队列。
We start by importing a Python built-in module that we will use for creating a priority queue.
这非常重要，因为当我们需要选择下一个要访问的城市时，不需要去遍历一大堆城市的列表来寻找离源节点最近的一个，
This is very important because instead of looking through a huge list of cities to find the closest one to the source node once we need to choose which cities we will visit next,
优先队列在这种情况下将是一个最小堆，因为我们要优先处理较小的值。
the priority queue, in this case it will be a min heap because we will prioritize the smallest value.
它会保留距离源点最短的城市，让程序能够立即获取到它。
It will keep the city with the shortest distance from the source where the program can have access to it immediately.
所以它会将我们需要的数值保持在随时可供程序使用的状态。
So it will keep the values that we are looking for ready to be used in the program.
接下来这一行定义了函数。
Then this line defines the function.
该函数接受两个参数。
The function takes two arguments.
一个是代表城市和道路的数据结构——图，另一个是源节点，也称为起始节点。
The graph, which is the data structure that represents the cities and roads, and the source node, also known as the start node.
这是整个过程的起点。
This is the starting point of the whole process.
然后我们定义 distances 变量。
Then we define the distances variable.
这个变量存储一个字典，用来记录从源节点到图中每个其他节点的最小距离。
This variable stores a dictionary that tracks the shortest distance from the source node to every other node in the graph.
最初，如果距离未知，该值就是无穷大。
Initially, that distance is infinity when it's unknown.
当然，源节点到自身的距离是零，所以我们初始化这个值。
Of course, the distance between the source node and itself is zero, so we initialize that value.
接着，我们初始化一个字典，将每个节点与算法找到的路径中的前一个节点关联起来。
Then we initialize a dictionary that associates every node to its previous node in the path, found by the algorithm.
最初这些值为空，但随着算法找到最佳路径，它们会被更新。
Initially, the values are none, but these are updated as the algorithm finds the best path.
我们还需要一个集合来存储已经访问过的节点。
And we also need a set to store the nodes that have already been visited.
然后我们初始化优先队列，也就是我们要接下来访问的城市或节点列表。
Then we initialize our priority queue, our list of cities or nodes to visit next.
这是一个我们需要接下来访问的城市或节点列表。
This is a list of cities or nodes that we need to visit next.
每个城市或节点都由一个元组表示，包含它到源节点的距离以及它的名称或标签。
Each city or node is represented by a tuple with its distance from the source node and its name or label.
我们需要这个距离，因为我们的实现总是查看配对中的第一个数字，来对接下来需要访问的节点进行排序。
We need the distance because our implementation always looks at the first number in the pair for sorting which nodes we will need to visit next.
所以它会根据哪些城市离源节点最近来进行排序，这正是我们寻找最短路径所需的。
So it will sort them based on which cities are closest to the source node, exactly what we need to find the shortest
之后，我们开始 while 循环，遍历尚未访问过的城市列表。
path. After that, we start the while loop that will iterate over the list of cities that we haven't visited yet.
然后我们调用 heap queue.heappop 方法，将优先队列作为参数传递给它，其中包含我们要接下来访问的城市列表。
Then we call the heap queue.heappop method, passing the priority queue the list of cities that we will visit next
作为参数。
as an argument.
这将弹出该城市，或者说取出该城市，并返回距离源节点最近的那个。
This will pop the city or it will take the city and then return it with the smallest distance to the source node.
然后我们使用这种语法，将当前到源节点的距离赋值给变量 current_distance，并将当前节点的名称赋值给变量 current_node。
Then we use this syntax to assign the current distance from the source node to the variable current distance and the name of the current node to the variable current node.
如果当前节点已经被访问过，我们就跳过本次循环的剩余部分。
If the current node has already been visited, we skip the rest of the iteration.
现在我们到了当前节点，我们需要从这里开始向前移动，来检查并更新它的邻居。还记得图中的那个步骤吗？
Now that we are at our current node, we need to start moving forward from it to check and update its neighbors. Remember that step from the diagrams?
这个循环遍历当前节点的直接邻居。
This loop iterates over the immediate neighbors of the current node.
在 for 循环中，对于每一个未访问的邻居，会将边的权重加到到该节点目前记录的距离上。
Within the for loop, for each unvisited neighbor, the weight of the edge is added to the current distance that has been recorded for that node so far.
我们基本上只是把新边加入到距离中，来找出可能的新源节点距离。
We basically just add the new edge to the distance to find what could be potentially the new distance from the source node.
如果新距离小于我们目前为该邻居记录的最佳距离，那么就会更新这个距离。
If the new distance is less than the best distance that we have recorded for that neighbor so far, the distance is updated.
因为这意味着我们找到了一个从源节点到该城市更短的路径。
Because that means that we found an even shorter path to the city from the source node.
同时，前一个节点也会被更新，以追踪最短路径。
Also, the previous node is updated to track the shortest path.
如果路径变短了，我们就需要更新它。
If the path is shorter and we need to update it.
然后我们将这个带有新距离的邻居推入优先队列，以便继续沿着这条路径探索。
And we push that neighbor with its new distance to the priority queue to continue exploring through that path.
当 for 循环完成时，我们通过将其添加到已访问节点集合中，将当前节点标记为已访问。
Once the for loop is completed, we mark the current node as visited by adding it to the set of visited nodes.
这就是 for 循环。最后，在 while 循环中，记住我们在 while 循环里嵌套了一个 for 循环。
This is the for loop. And finally, once the while loop, remember that we have a for loop nested within a while loop.
当 while 循环完成且所有节点都被访问后，图中每个其他节点到源节点的距离……
Once the while loop is completed because all nodes have been visited, the distances from the source node to every other node in the graph
并返回每个节点对应的上一个节点。
and the corresponding previous nodes for each node are returned.
这是图的输出结果。
This is the output for the graph.
如果你需要重构从节点 A 到节点 D 的最短路径，你可以实现这样一个函数。
If you need to recreate the shortest path from node A to node D, you can implement a function like this one.
它接收我们作为输出获得的上一个节点的字典以及目标节点。
It takes the dictionary of previous nodes that we got as the output and the destination node.
在这种情况下，目标是节点 D。
In this case, the destination was node D.
我们初始化一个空列表来存储表示路径的字符串，并定义一个变量来存储当前节点。
We initialize an empty list for storing the strings that represent the path and the variable to store the current node.
我们从目标点开始。
We start at the destination.
基本上我们在进行回溯，也就是向后倒推。
We are basically backtracking, we're going backwards.
然后只要当前节点不是空值（因为还没到达路径的起点），我们就继续把当前
Then while the current node is not none because we haven't reached the start of the path, we continue appending the current
节点添加到路径中，并将上一个节点赋值给序列中的当前节点。我们正在逐步向后移动。
node to the path and assigning the previous node to the sequence as the current node. We're moving backwards gradually.
当 while 循环结束时，我们反转路径并返回它，以确保顺序正确。
When the while loop is completed, we reverse the path and return it to get it in the right order.
即从源节点到目标节点的路径。
From the source node to the destination node.
这是一个调用我们刚刚定义的这些函数的例子。
This is an example of how you could call these functions that we've just defined.
你可以看到我们调用 Dijkstra 函数，并将图作为参数传入。
You can see that we call the Dijkstra function passing the graph as an argument.
你可以假设代码中已经定义好了这个图。
You can assume that the graph has already been defined in the code.
我们传入源节点 A，
We are passing the source node A,
并将返回值分别赋值给 distances 和 previous_nodes 变量。
and we are assigning the return value to the variables distances and previous nodes.
然后我们调用 get_shortest_path 函数。
Then we call the get shortest path function.
我们将 previous_nodes 变量作为参数，并传入目标节点 D，
We pass the previous nodes variable as argument and the destination node D
来获取到节点 D 的路径。
to get the path to node D.
然后我们打印出返回值，方便查看。
And then we print the return values so we can see them better.
这将是我们的图的输出结果。
This will be the output for our graph.
最短路径是从节点 A 到节点 B 再到节点 D。
The shortest path goes from node A to node B to node D.
从节点 A 到节点 D 的总距离是 7，因为我们会经过一条权重为 2 的边，再经过一条权重为 5 的边。
And the total distance from node A to node D is 7, because we would go through an edge of weight 2 and then an edge of weight 5.
这就是这个 Python 实现的工作原理。
And that's how this Python implementation works.
那么让我们回到那个著名的日子，因为有一件非常有趣的事情你应该知道，对吧？
So let's go back to that famous day because there is something very interesting that you should know, shall we?
你可能会想象 Dijkstra 坐在咖啡馆的桌子旁，在成百上千张纸上勾勒并集思广益，以此来找到正确的解决方案，
You might picture Dykstra very focused on his cafe table, sketching and brainstorming in hundreds of pieces of paper to come up with the right solution,
对吧？
right?
有趣的是，情况并非如此。
Interestingly, that's not how it happened.
Dijkstra 明确表示他并没有使用铅笔和纸，他是完全在脑子里构思出来的。
Dykstra literally said that he didn't use pencil and paper, he designed it entirely in his head.
他说他后来了解到，不用纸笔设计的一个优势是，你几乎被迫去避开所有可以避免的复杂性。
He said that he learned later that one of the advantages of designing without pencil and paper is that you're almost forced to avoid all avoidable complexities.
所以，这里的实践经验是，在脑子里构思可能有助于强迫自己追求简洁。
So, practical takeaway here, designing in your head may help you force simplicity.
他是一个主张简约的人。
He was an advocate for simplicity.
他把编程视为一种高智力的挑战。
He approached programming as a high intellectual challenge.
这种简洁，加上这个算法强大的原理，才让这项发明成为历史上最伟大的进展之一。
That simplicity, combined with the powerful principles of this algorithm, is what made this invention one of the greatest developments in history.
当时，Dijkstra 并不知道那 20 分钟将成为他成名的基石，通过开启我们甚至不知道存在的各种功能来改变世界。
At that time, Dykstra didn't know that those 20 minutes would become the cornerstone of his fame, reshaping the world by unlocking capabilities that we didn't even know
……存在的。
existed.
每当你找到去附近杂货店的最短路径时，你就在利用 Dijkstra 算法的力量。
Every time you find the shortest path to your local grocery store, you're using the power of Dykstra's algorithm.
Dijkstra 成为了计算机科学史上最重要的人物之一。
Dijkstra became one of the most important figures in computer science history.
他在 1972 年获得了 Turing Award，这是该领域最重要的奖项之一。
He received the Turing Award in 1972, one of the most important awards in the field.
甚至还有一个以他命名的年度奖项，就是分布式计算领域的 Edgar W. Dijkstra Prize。
And there's even an annual award named in his honor, the Edgar W. Dijkstra Prize in Distributed Computing.
这个故事证明了灵感可以来自最意想不到的时刻，以及伟大的发现如何能对人类的未来产生深远的影响。
This story proves how inspiration can come from the most unexpected moments, and how brilliant discoveries can have a profound impact in the future of humankind.
Dijkstra 真的用他那件耗时 20 分钟的杰作改变了世界。
Dijkstra literally changed the world with his 20 minute masterpiece.
希望你喜欢这段关于 Dijkstra 算法的简短介绍。
I hope you enjoyed this quick introduction to Dykstra's algorithm.
如果你想深入了解，我们在 Free CodeCamp 的 YouTube 频道上有大量的编程和计算机科学课程。
If you want to go deeper, we have tons of programming and computer science courses on the Free CodeCom YouTube channel.
所以请点赞这个视频，订阅频道，并看看你现在看到的这个视频。
So like this video, subscribe, and check out this video that you can see right here.